We are in the midst of the perfection of
giving and the harmony of giving, which is very
important in our path,
especially
our diamond vows and in the
practice of Vajrayana. You
will usually have to perform four kinds of
giving, which
are usually connected with the color
yellow. In these four types of giving, it is
usually placed here just to plant
a seed in your mind.
After you have
received the vows of
Vajrayana, you will
perform these acts of giving. The
first is
giving material things,
simple things. For example, giving money, giving
belongings, giving a cup of coffee,
things like that. And a
second way of giving
is called giving protection. The
name of the four
types of giving is marked. That protection
can be called
quantitative equality; it means that...  With regard
to everyone, in a balanced way,
I think in my life it's not that
people have many
different races or
different genders or people from
different countries. I think that
I've traveled and met
people from many
different places, treating
people from many different political backgrounds as if I were
treating everyone
equally. I think
we all have
differences, and knowing that we have
differences, but what
we need to pay special attention to, in
my case, for
those practicing the
Dharma, is dealing with people who
have
different worldviews. If you are on
the path of self-cultivation and you want to uphold
your vows, part of
that
is accepting others
who have
different worldviews. The third act of giving
is giving.  Regarding giving, it's quite a lot, and
again, it's like
a conversation on a
bus or somewhere in
that vow part. The fourth type of giving is
giving and love,
but it includes
not getting angry. It also includes speaking
sweetly and telling the
truth, telling the truth to everyone. That's also love. So those
are different types of giving.
When we talk about giving, there are different levels of giving.
When you walk on the path of
giving, and those are the things that the
Buddhas will do. You will learn
more about it later. I'm just sowing
those seeds, okay? Then, let's
consider it. It
doesn't seem like listening. It's like
listening like that, saying like that.
Next, it means helping
those who are in prison, criminals, and
we have
plans for those in
prison. Maybe we've been there before.
There's a prison in the north, and
I used to have
one in the middle of Phoenix. It's very
easy to get to that prison, so
it takes about 8 hours to get there.
He pointed out that
the
people in prison are
suffering, and there are a lot of them in the US.
I think I have the
largest number of prisoners in the
world, and Arizona is one of the
places where they build prisons because the land is
very cheap, and we have
prisons there, and because the
land is cheap, the
labor is also cheap. They say
it's a particularly
good thing if we do
this with the prisoners, and
we've been doing it for many
years. I think we did it
with
someone who had cancer, and they...  They
passed away, they passed away with a
unique experience of mine, which is that
everyone there was very, very
special, they were very kind, and the prison
warden, the director of
that prison, they loved their colleagues.
They loved my team.
I will show you
those pictures later, and one of the
good people, Niep Tu, who escaped from that prison,
is studying and doing
very well in his business. For example, at
Scot Dell, there is something
very beautiful, saman, and things like
that. It's going quite
well, and we are talking about him, he
is talking about
protecting others from
suffering in Tibetan. It could be
people we see walking
on the road or on the
river or something, or in
modern times, they could be
having problems, for example, traffic accidents,
car accidents.
If no one intervenes,
then if...  If you're the
first one there, you'll
stop that. I remember
something when I was going to the airport in Xon, and
I had to. I rented a car
and drove on the road. I was driving on
the wrong road, the wrong route,
but there was a car in
front of
me. And in Island,
the fields were all well-
maintained, all well-maintained for driving.
All the roads had
stones, and so I was
following that car. That car kept running
over
those stones,
and finally it broke and fell.
Finally, I stopped.
I stopped and I ran to the place and I
ran to it. Oh, are you guys
okay? We need to go to the hospital.
And I helped them into
my car. And I think it
was fun because they didn't know us. They did
n't know there was a Buddhist monk
carrying them in that car to go.
But if that's the
first thing to do, to
help others, then that's
part of giving. That's also part of the
perfection of giving.
Perfect giving once you commit to
following the Vajrayana path and the
Vajrayana vows, one of the
most wonderful forms of giving is protecting and helping
those who are in
trouble. There's a
tradition in Buddhism:
a summer retreat for the
masters usually lasts 2 to 3 months. During
the summer, we usually stay in a
low-lying meditation retreat. One of the main
reasons is that there are
many animals outside, and in
the summer, if you go outside,
you often have to kill those
animals. So,
according to tradition, the
monks usually do
n't walk on the grass during their summer retreat.
It's called
protecting animals
from the cold season to the
hot season, like something
important, you know. Just one
animal that's near you, and
if you help them, you take them and
put them in the water, that's very good.
Don't be lazy, and don't
think that their lives aren't
important. Their lives are as
important as your life is
to you. So, if
you have a chance to help an
insect, do it. It's
not about sitting
on the other side of the lake
and watching all the
animals all day, but about
helping those insects,
those bugs, to escape. In
general, help in any way you can, especially
cockroaches, especially
cockroaches. It means that,
secretly, it's related to prayers,
secret prayers,
because it gives them freedom to escape from the
canals.  Fear is the fourth
secret vow of giving. So,
this is very much about the
doctrine, and it's a book of
material, and I think I find it quite
great. It's quite
interesting when we talk about giving,
the protection from worry, it
doesn't mean about the
way. If you have a bug
on you and it's
enjoying your blood, it can also be
a form of giving. I have a
guru, they said that
I like giving my blood
to bugs, but
I can't do that. It's very
dangerous, but
they have some special diseases, so
you don't
necessarily have to do that. However, if
you have any opportunity to
save any living thing,
then do it, take advantage of it.
Don't let anyone know you might
become a bug next time.
Remember
that tip.  The car would be a kind thing
[Applause]
that he taught me, a respected one,
another of my nephews. You can
buy it on Amazon, it's very cheap, and it's
also made very
cheaply, it's like a
bug trap. We use jars to catch
bugs and put them in,
or for example,
flies, and I think I usually catch
those flies in about 30
seconds, 30, 30 years, and then I catch
those flies and I take them
outside
and look at them. But it also
takes quite a lot of effort. Uh,
maybe. My record is 20
flies for one day, and my record
is one, one, one, one jar, and I
get three flies, but of course, if
you see a fly or
a fly, or it's like it
has a battery, then you turn
it off,
it has a nest.  It has its own
special nest, and you catch it. And take it
out, take it out, and then the
bugs will fly away. I think
it's a really great thing. I
really like it.
It feels like a
vacuum cleaner, and it's really
fast. It's faster than a
jar, and sometimes it's
more effective. Sometimes with a jar, you
can write a bug in a
way that's unintentional, but it can
feel like you're in the desert,
living a
wild life. And I really like
this [music]. It's just a
simple movement of your hand that
can save another living
being.
When you do the work in
the air, when you do the work in the air, when
you do the meditation, it
means you're giving
them your breath, giving them your happiness, and it's also good.  It's
called the perfection of
giving, so practice
meditation in
your mind, in your contemplation.
You don't necessarily have to give
them $100; you can just
give them your breath.
That's also the perfection of
giving.
I like the image
[music],
I like it.
I used to work for 20
years. I used to go to the top of the
building and meditate. It's a
very nice place, and during lunchtime or
break time, you can even
give a pastry on
top of it. It's a very
nice place, and the most secret method is
the conversation with the Buddha in
your bathroom. Okay, I'll teach
you the secret meditation methods.
You'll go, and it will be very
difficult for you to find time to meditate
when you have to work in a
very cramped room.  I was sick, right? I
had to do it. I had to work in an
extremely busy room. I did
n't even have time to kill the
bad notebook. So I usually
went into the toilet, closed the door,
and sat down on the
toilet bowl. I just sat there for about
5 minutes. I think
everyone would think I had a
stomach problem, but I would fulfill
my vows. I just
sat there fulfilling my vows. It was
a little itchy, but it was
okay. And you, you have
privacy. No one can control
you. I just sat there and fulfilled
my vows. And one day I
decided I would talk to my future Buddha. And
what did he say?
He never answered me, but
I was like, "I know, I know,
Master, listen to me." Master,
can my future Buddha
see me? That's right, for example,
can the future Buddha see me?
Right now, I'm sitting
on the toilet in the bathroom, so I'm saying, "
Hello,
Teacher. I know that if you
have any advice
for me, I'm very open to
listening. Because the Buddha can
see the past, present, and future,
right? So the Buddha can
see you right here.
So you can talk to
him, and I think it's very healthy.
You can talk to
him like, 'How is he?
How can I get closer to
him? Can he help me with my practice?'
I think it's
very good, very good. Practice.
Practice, but don't speak with
too much malice.
I often use
my company office for
my practice. I've done a lot of
things. This means that
when we are studying a
very, very famous book that
was written over 3000 years ago..."  Before, it was written
about the activities of the Bodhisattva by the
Bodhisattva, and the teacher is currently re-examining it.
If you like Sanskrit,
we are also researching
Sanskrit, so you can learn
Sanskrit. Next, we will learn about
how to behave as a Bodhisattva. I had
a very wonderful discussion
about the book by the Master.
In his discussion,
it means giving away the perfection. So
what does that perfection mean? People often say it means
going, it
means another place in the
ocean, it is called
paramita, it means
giving away the
number of perfections. The six perfections are not six
perfections, and those six perfections
will bring you perfection. The six
perfections will lead you to
perfection. It's
not that
you give away something. It's perfect,
but the act of giving will help
you become perfect. It's not a Bodhisattva,
and it's a
Bodhisattva.  To make you
perfect, so that's what he said, that the
act of giving
paramita means the perfection
of giving, the perfection of
giving, and we say it's true,
the Buddha spoke about that. And some
people say it's not the
perfection of giving, so we
ask why, because there are still
poor people out there. Look, did the
Buddha ever live on
this planet? Did the Buddha
reach the level of a Buddha?
I think so. Did the Buddha
achieve perfection? Did the
Buddha achieve the
first perfection? Did the Buddha achieve the perfection of
giving? So why are there still
poor people here? Then
he said, "Yes, now
we will talk about the real meaning when
the perfection of giving doesn't
mean there are no more people, but
the readiness to give
in the mind of a Buddhist,
that is perfection. So the Buddha  There
is a perfection in giving, and
perfection means giving,
which means you are ready to try,
you are always ready to try. Why are there still
poor people if the Buddha is
a perfect giver? Why are there
still poor people? But it comes from
their side, it comes from their side. The
Buddha cannot give you the seed, the
Buddha cannot give you the
seed to find it. You need to give
yourself the seed.
Find the Buddha, give the perfect action, but
you don't listen. He gives the
perfect action, but your seed
is your seed. Do you really
want to hear something interesting?
I cannot give you anything.
When your grandfather gives you 100 dollars, who
really gave you 100 dollars? Only you
yourself give yourself 100 dollars.
I think giving
to family members who
have passed away in this era, in
this era...  You don't understand the
perfection of giving, but you
can still be perfect in
your giving, just like you
can't really protect
insects, right? If
they have seeds, you still protect them.
But if they don't have seeds, the moment
you touch the water,
you've already drowned them, you've already
killed them. You say, "Oh, I
tried to help
these insects, but in the end, I
killed them." So, you know,
perfection here doesn't mean that
perfection here means
that if you want to protect their lives,
you'll understand that. In education,
when you try to help others,
you are limited by their seeds,
and you have to understand that.
Otherwise, you won't have the
courage anymore. That's like, "Teacher, I
tried to help the little people,
but they were possessive of me, they
told me to go away."  Go to
hell, but it's okay, it's okay,
you're still giving,
you're still doing it perfectly. You can't
control the outcome of
your practice, but
you can't control what will
happen, but you will try, but should you try? Should
you try?
Should you do it with your fish?
I have a lot of
problems here, and every month
I've spent 20 years here to make offerings to
a place, to do the
low-level work. 20 years is a
very difficult job, and some people are
n't happy, some people have
a bad time, but it's like, "
Sorry, I'm just
trying to give you a
good place. I'm not trying to
do anything bad. I just want to help
you, so you can't
control what will
happen, but that means..."  Even if
you can't do it,
don't feel discouraged
like Bonny Sapa, like
his head is very stubborn. A
very stubborn head, like when you try to
help them. But then,
I'm sorry. If you're not happy,
I'll try tomorrow. I
'll try to make you happier
tomorrow. I can't be sure I
can make you happy;
it depends on
their seed. But you have
that responsibility. Try
your best to make them happy. But
never feel discouraged.
You can't control what
will happen, what will happen in
your good deeds. Don't give up on
going to the diamond mountain because
some people have had a
bad time there.  But,
well, do your best to
help others, and then
their seeds will be different. If
their seeds are different, maybe they
need patience. Don't
create bad seeds, and don't create
bad seeds of your own.
For example, "Oh, I'm sorry, because you're
not enjoying it here. Next month
I'll build you a swimming pool,"
or "I'm sorry, you don't like the things
here. I'm sorry, you don't like
this or that. I'm sorry." "
I'm sorry, but I will." It's
like you can't
control everything. Even
a Bodhisattva needs a sense of
humor. If
you feel very
tired today, will you go back and give
up? No, I'll try again
tomorrow. Don't be too serious,
don't be too serious. You
can't control
all the seeds of others.
If others...  Criticism, you're judging,
you can try to give this money for
time, and the Tho people say, "Oh no, no, I do
n't like food. I do
n't like food." Later, we
will try to make cakes that are
more delicious, like when you are
doing business. When you are in the
business of Buddhism, you
don't always listen to
customers and don't feel afraid.
Just keep your mouth shut
and continuously maintain the virtue of helping
others. Then the Buddha will
help us and help us
continue to help.
And what about those who criticize you? Do
you stop and watch Netflix?
I really like
movies about Ha
Quoc, but after watching it for a few hours,
I feel bored. And I
feel, "Oh my God, I have to go
back and become a Bodhisattva, that
's the
best business. You can't measure the
success of the Buddha."  According to the
economic scale of that country,
it's not related to
the seeds of the
people living in that country. You're
not the Buddha, you
can't judge the Buddha, you ca
n't judge
that economy. They didn't create that economy;
you are the ones who created it.
So they will help you realize
that.
If
the world has changed because of
people who don't practice, then
it's crazy, you know? It doesn't
mean they do
n't retain their own part. Anyone who isn't a Bodhisattva is
still a
giver, but you ca
n't judge them through
their economic foundation. It's
just that those people are still
there in their world. I have a
friend, a friend who is a god. I think
I'll tell you...  You hear, during
a three-week retreat, I had a
Christian friend. We grew up
together from around third grade. We
met when we were about 8 years old, and I... well,
I later reunited with him when I was about
60. I invited him,
and he came from Phoenix,
and we had a
very enjoyable conversation. He's a very good
Christian, a very
good person. He often goes to church because
it has a holy place. And when I was a
child, I used to go
outside and read the Bible in
his church, and I had
very long, deep conversations. It was kind of
mind-boggling.
Things about Bodhisattvas... I said, "Oh, why? Well,
theoretically, a
Bodhisattva only sees the good things,
and they live for a bubble.
Their life is extremely happy,
extremely beautiful, and everyone else is
suffering, and so..."  In
my religion, that
Bodhisattva is like living in a
Buddha's paradise, you
know, and the people
around him
are
suffering. I said I didn't
like that, and I asked, "
What do you think?" And then,
you know, you'll come to some
very strange things: someone
makes you suffer, someone makes you suffer,
someone creates you.
Then someone makes
you get cancer, and I
ask, "Is their bubble good for
me?" He says, "Let me
think about it." So I think
we're all living in a bubble,
we're all living in a
bubble, and we can't get out of it.
So we need to
give the gift of Dharma, to be able to
step out of
that bubble, but you can't
control their bubble.
Right, their bubble
comes from you, right? Uh, I
don't want to.  Sharing
your generosity is about the
perfection of giving. It's about
cultivating a positive attitude and achieving enlightenment. It's not
about physics; it's about the
willingness to give, to give what
you have. That's the perfection of
giving. For example,
other people's circumstances might
prevent them from seeing your generosity,
but your generosity,
your willingness to give, is the
perfection of giving. It
means that your willingness to
give. It means that you don't
give someone $1000
and then they go buy
something and spend it all.
We don't know what else to do, but
you can only do the
best you can. Be generous and help
others. You can't predict
what they will do with it; it
doesn't work that way.
Take what you have. It means
increasing your willingness to give.  The
true perfection of
giving is that you cannot control what
the world is doing. You
cannot control what people will do
with what you give. You
can only give. However, there is one
thing you shouldn't give away: do
n't give away
medicine to others, don't give
away things that will harm
others, and you need to do it in the
best way possible to avoid
hurting others. My point is, I know
there are wealthy parents who
hurt their children by giving them
too much, so their children
don't know what to do, they can't do anything
else. So it's not about the
quantity you give, but about giving
wisely, using your wisdom to
give. He said again, he was
talking about the monk,
the robe, the monk's robe.
If a poor person comes and says, "I want a
piece of cloth, I need a piece of cloth,"
then you need to be ready to have a  Being
ready to give is what makes giving
perfect. I
don't mean to say I
met someone who was very cold
and I was going skiing and I
gave them money, but actually,
generally speaking, you should give away
your scarf.
Actually, you do
n't necessarily need to give away your scarf.
But if you are
ready, you can share your room,
meaning start with
small things first, give small things
first. She said to give away
vegetables and fruits first.
Last night I gave
someone a lot of vegetables and fruits, and they always come
back with a plate and bowl, I don't
know why. So start with
simple, small things first, and
learn this way of giving to others, giving
small things first, then you
can build from
this foundation. It means starting with
small things first, then if...  You start with
small things first, and eventually
you can give away your whole body.
Start with small things
first, give away small things
all day long, and
after a while you can give away
your whole body. You
can grow
your generosity, your generous heart,
through giving away things,
starting with
small things,
and it's called persistence. Persistence in giving away small things,
and
we'll move on to the next picture. It's
difficult to
find a picture of a deceased person;
real life doesn't
like to be
posted
online. We will all die eventually,
we will all die eventually.
You can't have everything
you're afraid of;
you'll have to let go of it eventually. I
have a very beautiful diamond ring
in my pocket; I
always carry it with me.
Yesterday someone told me about
their 10-year-old child, and I thought, "Maybe
I'm going to give that child
my diamond ring," so I gave away
my diamond ring, and then I
started to regret it. I started to hate it, and
I thought, "Oh my God, maybe
my wife will be very sad," but then
I thought, "
If I keep it,
I still can't keep it. If I want to keep it,
I still can't keep it when I
die. I can't take it with me
anyway. Maybe when I die,
it will be in my pocket and they'll have to take it
away, or maybe they'll
take it,
or I'll write 'I'll
add it' on it, or I'll give it
away before I die. I don't
know anymore, those things... It's
like giving it to someone, right?
We might have a car accident
on the road, we don't know."
So, give something to
someone before it's too
late when you
die. You can't take anything
with you. So, if you
have something beautiful,
give it to someone else. Do
something kind before it's too
late, because sooner or later
someone will do the same
for you, and you'll feel
free when you give it away.
You might think, "Oh, I do
n't own anything." Yes, all those
good things are
just given away, given while
you have the ability.
Enjoy it while you
can. If it's really that annoying, it's quite a hassle to
let others clean up after
you. Now I don't know why
people do that. Now I'm going to clean
up that part. It's really quite annoying for
others. Believe
me, if you have a habit...
The point
of
moving
lightly is that your life
will be happier, understand? It will be much, much happier.
So, let's
limit it. I have a
pair of shoes, I have an outfit that I can
change every day, and I have something like that.
You can feel very
lighthearted. You will feel happy.
It will be very easy for you to
give. You need to always feel satisfied with
your giving. Continue to
maintain your giving. Give,
give. If someone asks you for
something, give it away. Keep giving.
Now, we have some
advice about giving
[music].
If you don't have
anything to give, but
you still want to make money, forget about
that. Oh
Thy, don't think R is... I am a
Buddhist, I need to give
more, give more to
Latin America so that I can be...  He
would hide a little. That's not
the perfection of it; it doesn't
count as generosity to achieve
something dishonestly and then give
it away. It doesn't count, so you
shouldn't give away fish,
and again, his audience
were all
monks. However, he had problems
in his time through
teaching those who kept
those people, and he, for example, could still
read books, but they had passed
away, but he was
criticized a lot for
teaching many
people three good deeds. The first is three
particularly suitable for
people who are not
monks. Why is that? Because
giving to the laity,
the second is that lay people often do business, and in family matters, they have more opportunities to live morally. The third is
patience, there's a
joke.  To not be
afraid, to not have to, to be able to
live in a monastic lifestyle,
it will require a lot of
patience. You will bother others. Yes, you
will bother others a little
outside the monastery, but I can say that
there are many
monasteries that have a mantra, a mantra that
comes from participating in the
Middle Way, that is called the
Buddha's teachings on emptiness.
Yes, I will teach you after
we finish this part, after
December. I believe, I think so. The
first thing for the three self-perfections
is that it is really good for the
lay
people. There are some things
you shouldn't do until
you reach that level.
Until you reach
that level, for example, giving away
your body is one of those things, or giving away your life. Giving away your body doesn't mean that...
Your body parts are
fine as long as you don't
die, and if you do
die because of someone else, we
don't have enough strength. So do
n't
give up on your abilities. Don't give up on
your body. You'll still need it. There will be
a day when you'll be fine, but they wo
n't be there anymore. All the words
they say, "Oh, you haven't reached
that point yet," but I say, "Oh, you're
ready," but you really aren't.
And he said it's not
appropriate to give away your
body,
and he said you're not
allowed to give away your body yet. Now
you
need to take care of your body. You need to
take care of your body. You have a
responsibility to take good care of
your body. Drink
healthily, practice
healthy exercise for your body.
Once you don't have a
You don't have the right to hurt it, you don't have
the right to over-exercise
your body. It's not your body, it's not you, and
your body is meant to be given to
others, so you need to have
a moral responsibility to maintain its
health. Maintaining
your health will one day come when giving
your body away will be as simple as
giving away your salad.
He said that when that time comes,
you can do it, but
you're not ready yet. So
if people try to
do that, they're just showing
off, they just want to be known by
others, they just want
others to know that they cut
off their finger. Take
care of your finger, don't show off. Do
n't pretend.
Don't pretend that you're
practicing things related to Bodhisattvas or
Buddhas. I have a friend
whose grandfather taught
us...  We have so many
stories and we are
[music]
There was a Mongolian temple, a
temple in Mongolia, and there was a
young man there, we studied there, and
this young man immediately
gave away all his belongings
and went across the river,
and
he would live like, and at the
very moment, on a cold day,
he came back, and it was really
fun, so forget about it. I used to
live in a cave, I
used to meditate in a cave, at
night it was like there was a whole day, I looked
there, and I felt like I thought
I should go back to the Diamond
and live in some kind of cave with a
door. He would also continue talking about
things that are not appropriate to
give
away, it is not appropriate for a
monk to give away his robe, his monk's
robe, I believe that. I mean,
unless they are too cold, or
things like that.  So, can I
announce something else, Chimy? Is that
okay?
Okay, I don't care. At 5:45, there
will be a ceremony.
You'll find there's a
performance,
and then you can
realize that if you can, if
you feel like it, then...
I have an idea: if
someone asks me whether they should let their child
marry,
my thinking is that a person who marries should
be someone outstanding, not
because of their
actions or their feelings, but because they have
a higher moral character, a
higher moral lifestyle. In
my opinion, you can say, "Well, this person is
a religious person or not, not
because of their hair,
not because of their clothes,
but because they are kinder and
more moral. They reject an
immoral lifestyle, and I think that's the
way."  So that you can
determine whether someone is a
monk or not, and through
their actions as well, I think that
for some people, the way they
style their hair or wear their clothes can be
bothersome. In the past,
if you were
close to them, it would be
quite bothersome if they
wore a monk's robe or had a
haircut. Fewer people would
talk to them. I've seen
monks in the West,
and it seems like very few people can
talk to them, and therefore they can't
converse with
others. So I really have a
strong feeling that if
you want to ask me, I think
you should
agree with my opinion. If you
don't like it, you can ask another monk to ordain you,
cut your hair, or
give you the robes, even if your parents...  I
don't want to talk to you anymore.
Nobody wants to talk to you. What I mean is,
it's also difficult. If you
want that, if you want to become a monk
or nun from your grandfather, then I'm
not selling clothes, I'm not selling the
previous style, but I'm
selling actions, actions. I'm selling
actions that are extremely, extremely
ethical, and I believe that a monk or
nun should be
distinguished by their actions,
not by their appearance.
For me, that's what
true monastic life is, that's the
kind of monastic life I'm offering.
It's truly very special for
those who become monks or nuns.
If someone is about to
die from the cold,
you can give away your robe
in 10 seconds and it'll still be okay. But that's
not appropriate when you give
away a robe.  There are some gifts for spiritual
masters, like food after lunch.
For example, monks, like those
given after
lunch, they don't have that right; they don't
eat those things, they don't
receive those things. There's a
tradition that when you
become a monk, you have the
right to choose
whether or not to skip your lunch after lunch.
I've skipped it for
15 years now. I haven't eaten
lunch after lunch for 15 years. Then I
started doing
yoga, and then I felt I
needed to eat lunch. Because of
my yoga schedule, I still had to eat, so
I changed
my habit. So, according to
this
ancient tradition, a spiritual master or monk should
n't have lunch after lunch. But
according to this
current tradition, when you become a monk,
you have the right to
keep it.  One day or keep it
for the rest of your life, it
depends on you. I truly believe
that right now, I don't have Ann
after the afternoon anymore. I don't have him
usually, so I won't have him
in the afternoon and the last time.
I think it's
very healthy, it helps me
in my business career.
I don't eat after 12 o'clock throughout my business career, and
I believe it helps
my mind stay clear, it's
very useful, but it depends on
you.
She said that monks
and even
non-monks, those who are not
Buddhist, are
not allowed to eat onions or garlic.
She said
it's inappropriate to offer
onions and garlic to a monk.
She said
there are some animals that live
underground, so they do
n't eat them.
Without Ann, they don't have
onions, they say that you might
kill some small living things
to give something
that is inappropriate for someone
from another religion. It's not a good deed. It
means that the food has a smell.
In the monastery, like where
you live, you
live close to other people and
you discuss things for two to three hours
each day. It's not appropriate for
onions or
garlic to create discomfort for
others. In general,
monks do
n't eat food with a smell.
If
someone has the intention of judging,
it's also inappropriate. For example,
giving a scripture to
someone who
intends to tear it up is
also inappropriate,
meaning it's a
death sentence.  It means they want to die, they want to pass
away, and it could also mean helping
someone who wants to
harm others. It's not appropriate to
sell weapons or
alcohol, to give away anything that will
hurt them. If
someone wants to commit suicide, you
wouldn't be
a good Bodhisattva if you gave them
a weapon. You
can buy me a
gun, can't you? And you say no,
but you are a Bodhisattva. That's right,
I have a vow to
give away what people ask for,
so buy me a gun. No,
no, it doesn't mean
you have to give away everything. If
it harms others, if it
hurts others, then don't
give it
away. You certainly shouldn't allow the
secret teachings to be shared with
those who are not ready.  Or perhaps those
who haven't yet taken refuge properly...
I had two nightmares
this week. I rarely have nightmares like this;
I ca
n't remember. I have a
friend who has nightmares every night. Every
month they wake up saying they're being
chased, that someone is chasing them. So I've
never had those nightmares before,
but I remember having two of
them recently, and I
was very surprised. I
had a nightmare about
people practicing the Vajrayana tradition
incorrectly, or about people practicing the tradition
without following the rules. I
had two nightmares about it, so I
think you need to
know about the principles of
walking the Vajrayana path.
If you have any weaknesses in the
Secret Teachings from your grandfather, then the
private rights of your maternal grandfather are
yours.  You need to complete the
18 basic AC courses to move on to
the higher level. I think most of
them have failed, I think
most of them have failed, so please do
n't share the secret teachings
and say that you have completed the 18
basic AC courses. That's what Grandpa requires,
and don't share it on
internet platforms. 12, 18 courses,
those 18 courses are the best in the world, the
best, the most amazing in history,
and I think it's about two or
two pages long. I think you don't
need to look any more upfront online or find any more
information.
Because it's not something you
memorized from anyone's teachings, you
don't need it. If
you have completed 20,000 pages
and you want more, let me
know. I will check your homework
first, and then I will share it with
you.  There are many other
strange and extremely gentle things, but
don't waste your time
on the path of Vajrayana Buddhism.
It is already very perfect, and it is the
most perfect path in the
history of Buddhism in the world. It is very sacred, very pure, very
virtuous, very
wonderful, very lovely. It is a very wonderful
practice. So
don't waste your time on it.
Don't give me any more of
that evil stuff. It's very bad.
You don't need any more of that.
If you have 20,000 pages and
you are still not completely satisfied, then
come and ask me, and I will share
with you many more strange things.
Furthermore, it's not about
the things on the mother anymore; it's not
suitable. It's not the path
to all the ways of reading about
orthodox nectar. As for the 18 courses,
believe me, there is nothing more than 18
courses.  It's not that, it's a lifelong practice.
You can practice it
throughout your life, but you
still won't get close to the
end. So
don't make me lose
another hair. I'll be more, I'll be
more,
meaning teaching
deeper teachings to those who haven't
completed the 18 basic courses. It means
those who aren't suitable, not
suitable, and I've tried it before. I've met
people I think are very
special. But actually, it
's a crisis, so
you guys stay safe. Make
sure they've completed the 18
foundational courses. Otherwise, if they're not
ready to complete 18 months, then 18
courses, they can't succeed
in their practice. The point is,
don't do
that. Is it a miraculous
activity related to the real religion in
building more organizations,
releasing more prisoners? No, no.
It's not that it will hurt
many people, but rather that they have to
try to create a real number
in that country and lock them up.
I would say it's not kind to
manage the danger, to befriend someone who can
hurt
others. But if we
can help them, we should. You
can go to their prison, to
their prison, and dedicate
your life to teaching those prisoners.
You can do this for 6 to 10
years. And if anyone
thinks they
can be freed, then help
them. But it doesn't mean
you should free everyone.
There are some things in
life that you don't have, so give them
to others, for example, people who
want to accumulate wealth or
people who want convenience.
Things like that,
becoming a Bodhisattva isn't about giving
everything away, but about giving everything with a
responsible heart without
hesitation. I know we still have
two more classes like this, but
please stay. I believe that
when I was teaching and cooking
in a class in India, I
made my students endure even
more than that. When the day came, the day was over, and
I
left. Never give something away
without appreciating what you
will receive in return. For example, they say it's
not wrong to think that way: if I save
$100, I
will receive $100, and if I save $1000,
we have 3 minutes left.
This is about the
ethics of giving and making
difficult decisions, and being a Bodhisattva.
Sometimes you have to make
difficult decisions. When you have
a lot of money and a lot to give,
the decision of
who you give to is
very important. It's not about
throwing your money away. I
once asked my guru, "
Guru, there are so many
homeless people out there in New York,
should I help them?" My guru
said no. He said, "You should do
what's best for you. Make
sure you don't give them
money to buy things or anything like that." But
if you want to help
a student or a homeless child, there
are no limits;
we can't give everything to everyone.
You have to make
difficult decisions about where
you give and where you give.  We
will contribute to the work of whoever
we should give to, and you also need
to enjoy that and also need to
have a
correct judgment, just like in the aesthetic
part of cosmetic surgery.
You need to be firm with
your work. It's not that I'm
contributing to my plan, and I
want to see the results.
I will never forget to contribute to fundamental
things like that. It's very
good to be firm with
your position. It's like a
responsibility. So I will contribute to
your plan, but I
want to see the results.
I want to see that
your calculations are clean and accurate, and
if they are not clean, I
want my money back so
I can give it to someone else. So
it's part of giving like
a Bodhisattva, giving with
responsibility.  Regarding the matter of giving, yes, I will give what
you want. But I want to
make sure that you are using
that money correctly. If it's
right, then they
want it,
and they want that you need to
prove that you are using it properly. You
need to be firm when you give away
your money.
And one last thing, we've never
had a single
theft in my company, and we've had to. There
were 300,000 diamonds a day, and
a table, for example, a table, that was worth
millions of
dollars. And we had tables that
they covered in diamonds. And I once
had a conversation with a
business partner, and he said, "
Oh my." You know, you're a kind-hearted
person, you trust
people, but don't make
it easy for people to
steal from you because you'll hurt
them because not everyone is the same.  In reality,
they might just give up a hand
and... well, you
know. You need a
system, you need security gates, you
need cameras, you need
guards. And that's also part of a Bodhisattva. A
Bodhisattva needs to respect
other people's property. A Bodhisattva must also make
sure that it's not easy for
others to steal their belongings because when
they do, they will hurt
themselves. We need to make sure that they
won't hurt themselves by not
making it easy for them to
steal our things.
Protect others from others,
protect them from themselves.
When I worked in
that business, I learned a
lot from it. I said, "I
don't like the idea of ​​suspecting
others. I will definitely put
my reins on the horse, and you, my friend,
don't do that. They're not as strong
as you. They'll just throw it away and they'll mix it in."  That's how it is,
and then you
're the one who brings them to that problem,
that problem, so it's really
not easy to prevent
others from creating new problems for
themselves.